Finding Aid to the Save the Redwoods League photograph collection. 1885-2014
The Bancroft Library
- Series 6: Photographer Files., 1918-2006; carton 8; fALB v.11-14; NEG boxes 2, 4-9; NNEG boxes 1, 2, 5
  - Evan Johnson Collection., 1993-2006; carton 8; NEG boxes 2, 6
    - Corridor from the Redwoods to the Sea, celebration and general photos, slides and negatives., May 19, 2000; 3 folders 236 35mm color slides, 5 rolls of b&w and color negatives. (Neg box 6)
      For matching contact sheets and prints see: Vertical Files -- Corridor from the Redwoods to the Sea, Johnson photographs.
    - Eel River, color slides., circa 1999?; 11 35mm slides. (Neg box 6)
      Man and woman with a child in the redwoods.
    - Headwaters, color transparencies., circa 1999?; 21 sheets of 2.25 x 3.75 in. transparencies. (Neg box 6)
      Includes Grizzly Creek and clear cut areas.
      It is unclear whether some are Don Briggs or Evan Johnson photographs. Both were formerly in the same 3 ring binder.
    - Headwaters, contact sheets., circa 1999?; 21 color contact sheets. (Carton 8)
    - Humboldt/Dyerville, color slides., 1996; 18 35mm slides. (Neg box 6)
      Includes people on redwood logs.
    - Ladybird Johnson Grove, color slides., circa 2000?; 14 35mm slides. (Neg box 6)
      Includes woman walking in the grove, Redwood National Park.
    - Mill Creek site visit, slides and negatives., December 15, 2000; 80 35mm slides and 3 rolls of 35mm negatives. (Neg box 6)
      Slides do not have matching prints. Selected negatives have matching prints.
    - Mill Creek site visit, contact sheets and prints., December 15, 2000; 2 contact sheets and 11 4 x 6 in. prints from selected negatives. (Carton 8)
    - Miscellaneous subjects, slides., circa 1993-1998; 41 35mm color slides. (Neg box 6)
      Includes beach scenes, people backpacking, camping and hiking, disabled people bicycling and Don Murphy.
    - Montgomery Woods, color negatives., 2006; 4 sheets of 2.25 x 2.25 in. film. (Neg box 6)
    - Montgomery Woods, contact sheets., 2006; 4 contact sheets for all negatives and 1 CD with printout of image (duplicate of negative). (Carton 8)
    - Montgomery Woods and Mexia, color negatives., circa 2006; 13 sheets of 2.25 x 2.25 in. film. (Neg box 6)
    - Montgomery Woods and Mexia, contact sheets and copies., circa 2006; 2 folders 13 contact sheets, 1 CD with 1 image, map and notes. (Carton 8)
      Includes Daly Grove.
    - Northern groves, color negatives., circa 1999?; 26 rolls of 35mm, 2.25 x 2.25 in. film, and 1 CD with 1 image. (Neg box 6)
      Strip that includes image on CD is missing.
    - Northern groves, contact sheets., circa 1999?; 26 contact sheets. (Carton 8)
    - Prairie Creek, color slides., 2 folders; 161 35mm slides. (Neg box 6)
      Adults and children hiking and camping.
    - Save-the-Redwoods League seventy-fifth anniversary, b&w negatives and slide., October 1993; 19 rolls of 35mm film and1 35mm slide. (Neg box 2)
      <list type="marked"> <item></item> <item></item> <item></item> </list>
      Celebrations at the Founders Grove and Federation of Women's Clubs Grove.
      For matching contact sheets of the negatives see: Vertical Files -- Save the Redwoods League -- Seventy-fifth anniversary celebration -- Johnson contact sheets. See also: Album volumes 6-7. Color slide does not have a matching print.
    - Wolf Creek, color slides., circa 1999?; 67 35mm slides. (Neg box 6)
      Children on a field trip and interacting with park rangers.
  - Howard King Collection., 1964-1987; fALB v.12; NEG boxes 4, 7
    Negatives and color transparencies, and matching contact sheets by photographer Howard King.
    Numbers probably refer to dates taken (32464 is probably March 24, 1964). Album contains item list with locations of photographs.
    - 4x5 inch color negatives, 32464 to 60187., 1964-1987 (Neg box 7, Sheets 1-88)
      Includes 1 8 x 10 and 2 5 x 7 transparencies (duplicates of color negatives).
      - Mill Creek, Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park., December 5, 1964; King, Howard; BANC PIC 2006.030--NEG; 1 photograph (Neg box 7)
        Dirt road curving through the redwood trees.
        Negative 120564-3. Print available elsewhere in collection.
        Coast redwood -- California -- Pictorial works; State parks & reserves -- California; Landscape photographs; Del Norte County (Calif.)
      - Fern Canyon, Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park., July 4, 1965; King, Howard; BANC PIC 2006.030--NEG; 1 photograph (Neg box 7)
        Stream between fern covered, cliff walls.
        Negative 70465-2. Print available elsewhere in collection.
        This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection
        Coast redwood -- California -- Pictorial works; State parks & reserves -- California; Landscape photographs; Humboldt County (Calif.)
    - Contact sheets for 4x5 inch, color negatives, 32464 to 60187. (Falb v.12)
    - 4x5 inch black and white negatives, 13165 to 52266., 1965-1966 (Neg box 7, Sheets 89-94)
    - Contact sheets for 4x5 inch black and white negatives, 13165 to 52266., 1965-1966 (Falb v.12)
    - 120 film, color negatives, 32564 to 111377., 1964-1977 (Neg box 7, Sheets 95-151)
    - Contact sheets for 120 film, color negatives, 32564 to 111377., 1964-1977 (Falb v.12)
    - 120 film, black and white negatives, 22370 to 22570., 1970 (Neg box 7, Sheets 152-153)
    - Contact sheets for 120 film, black and white negatives, 22370 to 22570., 1970 (Falb v.12)
    - Miscellaneous color transparencies., March 1964; 2.25 x 3.5 in. transparencies and 35mm slides. (Neg box 7)
      Includes Alder Grove in Prairies Creek Redwoods State Park, Pepperwood Grove parcel 15 or 17, and an unidentified river.
    - Copy negatives and matching contact sheets., 1964; 2 folders (Neg box 4)
      Negatives seem to all be duplicate negatives. Arrangement meaning undetermined. Contact sheets lacking identification, therefore shelved together with negatives, which are annotated with photographer's numbers.
  - Emerson Knight Collection., 1927-1939; fALB v.11; NNEG boxes 2, 5
    Original negatives by photographer Emerson Knight, and modern contact sheets of the negatives.
    - Negatives for "Human Values of the Redwoods" (EK-A1 to EK-Z3)., July 1939; 2.25 x 3.5 in. b&w negatives. (Nneg box 5)
      Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park, Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park, Humboldt Redwoods State Park and Redwood Highway.
    - Negatives of Monterey County and Mexican highway study (EK-Z4 to EK-Z24)., 1925, 1938, undated; Approximately 5 x 7 in. b&w negatives. (Nneg box 2)
    - Modern contact sheets for negatives EK-A1 to Z24. (Falb v.11)
      Includes "Human Values of the Redwoods," Monterey County and Mexican highway study.
      Item list in album.
    - Miscellaneous Emerson Knight negatives., July 11-16, 1927; 6 2.25 x 3.5 in. b&w negatives. (Nneg box 5)
      Includes adobe building, palm trees, and building that looks similar to San Francisco Solano Mission in Sonoma.
      Negatives received from Save the Redwoods League in annotated envelope, but description is questionable. Handwritten on envelope: Mr. Newton B. Drury, Save the Redwoods League. Trip of EK [Emerson Knight] into Prairie Creek, Humboldt County, California.
  - Martin Litton Collection., 1964-1965; NEG box 5
    Original negatives by photographer Martin Litton.
    - Martin Litton negatives, AAA 2-67, and unnumbered., 1964-1965; 77 4 x 5 in. b&w negatives. (Neg box 5)
      Includes Lost Man Creek; logging and freeway construction in and near Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park; logging in Gold Bluffs Beach area; land logged by Simpson Timber Company; Upper Berry Glen cut.
      Many negatives are copy negatives.
  - David Swanlund Collection., fALB v.13-14; NEG boxes 8-9
    Original negatives and matching contact sheets by photographer David Swanlund.
    - Item lists for David Swanlund collection. (Falb v.14)
    - Negatives DS-1 to DS-683., 4 x 5 b&w negatives. (Neg box 8)
      - Logging by Arcata Redwood Company, Redwood National Park area., April 12, 1975; Swanlund, David; BANC PIC 2006.030--NEG; 1 photograph (Neg box 8)
        Negative DS-683. Photograph also numbered 4644. Print available elsewhere in collection.
    - Contact sheets for negatives DS-1 to DS-683. (Falb v.13)
    - Negatives DS-P1 to DS-P5 (Projects 1 to Project 5)., 4 x 5 in b&w negatives. (Neg box 9)
    - Contact sheets for negatives DS-P1 to DS-P5 (Projects 1 to Project 5). (Falb v.14)
    - Negatives DS-B-1 to DS-B-648., 2.25 x 2.25 in. b&w negatives. (Neg box 9)
      Includes some random duplicates within the number range of DS-B-7 to DS-B-390.
    - Contact sheets for negatives DS-B-1 to DS-B-642. (Falb v.14)
    - Negatives DS-C-1 to DS-C-142., 2.25 x 2.25 in. color negatives. (Neg box 9)
      Includes 1 duplicate for DS-C-81A.
      - Dignitaries on stage at dedication of Lady Bird Johnson Grove, Redwood National Park., August 27, 1969; Swanlund, David; BANC PIC 2006.030--NEG; 1 photograph (Neg box 9)
        On stage from left to right: Rev. Billy Graham, Governor Ronald Regan, Congressman Don Clausen, Lady Bird Johnson (hidden), Secretary of Interior Walter J. Hickel, President Richard M. Nixon, Pat Nixon, Former President Lyndon B. Johnson, Mrs. Julie Eisenhower, David Eisenhower, Mrs. Luci Nugent, Patrick Nugent, Mrs. Lynda Robb, Charles Robb, Senator George Murphy, Mrs. Hale Boggs, Senator Hale Boggs.
        Negative DSC-8a. Print available elsewhere in collection.
        Conservation of natural resources -- California; National parks & reserves -- California
      - Dedication of Drury Visitor Center, Redwood National Park., October 20, 1973; Swanlund, David; BANC PIC 2006.030--NEG; 1 photograph (Neg box 9)
        Newton B. Drury about to cut ribbon. Left to right: Congressman Don Clausen; Newton B. Drury; John Davis, Superintendent of Redwood National Park; Ronald Walker, Director of National Park Service; Mrs. Newton B. Drury.
        Negative DSC-26B. Photograph also numbered 4468. Print available elsewhere in collection.
    - Contact sheets for negatives DS-C-1 to DS-C-142. (Falb v.14)
    - Negatives DS-1-C (DS-622), DS-2-C (DS-624), DS-3-C, DS-4-C., 4 x 5 in. color negatives. (Neg box 9)
    - Contact sheets for negatives DS-1-C (DS-622), DS-2-C (DS-624), DS-3-C, DS-4-C. (Falb v.14)
    - Negatives 414, 416, 4733, 5090, 5201-5206, and unnumbered., Color negatives, b&w negatives and color transparencies. (Neg box 9)
      Includes Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, Prairie Creek, Hyatt Grove, Dyer, Kellie Owen, Mexia, Fern Canyon, and Cheatham Grove.
      No contact sheets available.
- Series 7: Miscellaneous Negatives and Lantern Slides., circa 1920s-1930s; NEG(gl) boxes 1-9; NNEG boxes 8-9
  Arranged alphabetically in three subseries: Glass negatives, Lantern slides, Miscellaneous film negatives.
  Miscellaneous glass negatives, lantern slides and unidentified film negatives with no matching photographic prints. Negatives that have matching or related prints are described with the prints in the other series.
  - Glass negatives., 1927, undated; NEG(gl) boxes 1-4
    - Battle of San Pasqual [plaque]., 1927 (Neggl box 1)
      San Pasqual Battlefield State Historic Park, Escondido. Olmstead Survey photo. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G3.
    - [Father Junipero Serra Monument, Presidio of Monterey.] (Neggl box 1)
      Olmstead Survey photo. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G4.
    - James Marshall Monument., 1927 (Neggl box 1)
      Marshall Gold Discovery State Historic Park, Coloma. Olmstead Survey photo. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G5.
    - North Grove, Calaveras Big Trees., 1927 (Neggl box 1)
      Man standing in front of redwood tree. Calaveras Big Trees State Park. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G6.
    - Sutters Mill. (Neggl box 1)
      Coloma. McGurry photo. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G7.
    - [Marsh, wetland with hill.] (Neggl box 2)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G8.
    - [Lake with horseback riders in distance.] (Neggl box 2)
      Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G9.
    - [Landscape with two men.] (Neggl box 2)
      Copy negative?
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G10.
    - [Road near ocean and telephone pole.] (Neggl box 2)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G11.
    - [Climbers on mountains.] (Neggl box 2)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G12.
    - Chico Creek from bridge near mouth, looking downstream., November 7, 1925 (Neggl box 2)
      Bidwell State Park. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G13. Index number: 1759.
    - Fort Ross., 1927 (Neggl box 3)
      Bird's-eye view of area around the fort and coast. Fort Ross State Historic Park. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G14.
    - [Waterfall, Bidwell State Park.], 1927 (Neggl box 4)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G15.
    - [Creek.] (Neggl box 4)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G16.
    - Fort Tejon. (Neggl box 3)
      Dorman Bros. Copy negative.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G17.
  - Lantern slides., prior to 1928; NEG(gl) boxes 4-8
    All lantern slides have been colored. Some dates are questionable.
    - Butano Redwoods., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 4)
      Butano State Park. Photo by General Photographic Work (Gabriel Moulin?).
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G25.
    - Butano Redwoods., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 4)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G26.
    - Butano Creek, N. Fork., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 4)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G27.
    - Falls, Butano Creek., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 4)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G28.
    - Jordan Creek Bridge, after cutting., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 4)
      Photo by Gabriel Moulin, General Photographic Work.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G29. Additional number on label: SRL 415. Date is questionable, car is much later date.
    - Jordan Creek Bridge, after cutting., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 5)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G30.
    - Devastation, Samoa., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 5)
      Copy 1. Photo by Gabriel Moulin, General Photographic Work.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G31. Additional number on label: SRL 418.
    - Devastation, Samoa., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 5)
      Copy 2. Photo by Gabriel Moulin, General Photographic Work.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G32.
    - Last stand of Monterey Cypress, a veteran., prior to 1928
      Point Lobos State Reserve. Photo by Gabriel Moulin, General Photographic Work.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G33.
    - State highway, Castle Crags., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 5)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G34.
    - The Narrows, Painted Canyon, near Mecca., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 5)
      Photo by Tasker.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G35. Additional number on label: 87
    - Bodega Bay., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 5)
      Sonoma Coast State Park.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G36. Additional number on label: 25.
    - Undercutting a redwood tree, California., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 6)
      Photo by H.C. Tibbitts.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G37. Additional number on label: 16776.
    - Cross section of sequoia., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 6)
      Yosemite National Park.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G38. Additional number on label: 16.
    - [Field with wildflowers.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 6)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G39. Additional number on label: 159.
    - [Bathers on river bank.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 6)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G40.
    - [Redwood grove.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 6)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G41.
    - [Shoreline.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 6)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G42.
    - [Log cabin.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 6)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G43. Additional number on label: 214.
    - [Pasture with cows.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 7)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G44.
    - Knobcone pine cone (pinus tuberculata)., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 7)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G45.
    - [Adobe structure.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 7)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G46.
    - [Lumber yard.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 7)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G47.
    - [Front of Spanish style home.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 7)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G48.
    - Shall it be this? State Redwood Park, public welcome., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 7)
      Illustration of a park.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G49. Additional number on label: SRL 164.
    - Or this?, prior to 1928 (Neggl box 7)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G50.
    - Scenes of devastation following lumber operations, Humboldt County., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G51.
    - [Map of California showing sequoia ranges.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Photo by H.C. Tibbitts
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G52.
    - Bolling Memorial Grove in honor of a hero of the World War, Humboldt Redwood Park., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Humboldt Redwoods State Park.
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G53. Additional number on label: 121.
    - Bolling Grove [dedication plaque.], prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Humboldt Redwoods State Park. Photo by H.C. Tibbitts
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G54.
    - Garden Club Grove, showing South Fork of Eel River at Kerr Creek., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G55. Additional number on label: 11.
    - Garden Club Grove, Kerr Creek., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G56. Additional number on label: 8.
    - Garden Club Grove., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G57. Additional number on label: 2
    - South Calaveras Grove, Big Trees., prior to 1928 (Neggl box 8)
      Francis Farquhar, H.A., Elmer Reynolds and Hank Reese or John H. Elliott on horseback at the base of a redwood tree. Photo by General Photographic Work (Gabriel Moulin?).
      Save the Redwoods League inventory number: G58.
  - Miscellaneous film negatives., circa 1920s-1930s; NNEG boxes 8-9
    Miscellaneous film negatives that are unidentified, or have questionable identification, and are lacking prints. Bulk are landscapes, especially with redwood trees, and are probably in Humboldt County, California.
    The majority of these negatives were received from Save-the-Redwoods League foldered amongst the Humboldt County Photographic Survey photographs.
    - "Meeting places.", circa 1920s-1930s?; 6 photographs: negatives (Nneg box 8)
      Redwood groves and picnic areas.
      Negatives from envelope removed from Newton B. Drury correspondence files, 1920s-1980s.
    - Miscellaneous negatives (approximately 4x5 inch and smaller)., circa 1920s-1930s; 44 photographs: negatives (Nneg box 8)
      Miscellaneous subjects, the bulk of which are landscapes with redwood trees. Most locations are probably Humboldt County or Northern California. Includes coastal views; rivers, some which could be South Fork of the Eel River; dirt and paved roads, some which could be the Redwood Highway; tree stumps; cabins; people standing by redwood trees; baby in a basket; "Hays prop." Some negatives dated April1931, and could be related to Hartsook's and Gillogly, Humboldt County, negatives of the same date.
    - Miscellaneous negatives (approximately 5x7 inch)., circa 1920s-1930s; 65 photographs: negatives (Nneg box 9)
      Various landscapes, most which are probably in Humboldt County or Northern California. Some could be Lane Grove/Fish Creek area. Includes redwood trees; rivers, some which could be South Fork of the Eel River; dirt and paved roads, some which could be the Redwood Highway; clear-cut or fire damaged areas; coastal views; meadows; pastures; buildings in rural areas and cabins; people next to cross section of trees; Joshua trees; "The Little Red Hen"; "Plummer".
      One negative from envelope labeled: Blackburn negative, 1945 annual report.
- Series 8: Miscellany., 1963-1999; PIC boxes 3-4; OBJ box 1
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Includes an index of four-color printing done by Save the Redwoods League, photo library index cards, and ceremonial pens and plaques.
  - Index of four-color printing done by Save the Redwoods League., 1963-1999 (Pic box 3, Folders 1-32)
    Samples of print material ordered by Save the Redwoods League for distribution. Includes postcards, fliers, leaflets, pamphlets, brochures, bulletins, articles and membership certificates.
    Material originally assembled by Save the Redwoods League staff in two 3-ring binders. Material removed from binders and foldered by Bancroft Library staff.
  - Photo library index cards. (Pic box 4)
    Arranged alphabetically by location, with miscellaneous at the end of the file.
    3x5 index cards that provide written information about photographs, bulk of which are of parks in Northern California. Cards are arranged by park or location. Information includes location, photo number, date taken (circa 1964-1987).
  - Ceremonial pens and plaques., 1966-1998 (Obj box 1)
    Framed pens used to sign legislation establishing Redwood National Park (Lyndon B. Johnson, 1968) and Headwaters Forest Reserve (Pete Wilson, 1998); an American Motors Conservation Award presented to the League in 1966; and a plaque presented by the California Department of Forestry commemorating the League's 75th anniversary in 1993.